<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Helen Tran; Product Designer</title>
		<description>Helen Tran is a Product Designer working in technology. She blogs about tech life and design.</description>		
		<link>http://helentran.com</link>
		<atom:link href="http://helentran.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>From the Desk of the Politely Angry</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I sat in the audience while someone stood in front of me using sex and women as punchlines in his talk. Throughout the hour, he flashed hentai images, a gif of a monkey masturbating, and stopped scrubbing a video on a frame of a woman to remark, “Nice rack.” All this while littering his talk with dick jokes and an explanation of a conceptual video which centered around the idea of the domination of a woman. To my astonishment, his talk was punctuated by the sound of laughter from a handful of people in the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did nothing. I sat there and gave him my time and attention. When he finished, I filed out of the theatre with the other conference attendees and tried to sort through my thoughts amongst the many praises I overheard, “Wow, he was amazing!” I stood waiting for my colleagues and did not say much until someone confirmed what had happened. I had not imagined it. What I saw was the status quo of the industry standing so triumphantly on stage masked under the pretense of talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;seperator small&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear from other women in the industry about things like this happening. Admittedly, I brush them off and wonder if they are overreacting or if they are overly sensitive. I contrast their reactions against what I consider to be acceptable or inappropriate as I, egotistically, consider my barometer to be somehow &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; correct. I tell myself, “Well, you have quite a crass sense of humour. What if it is them and they cannot take a joke?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was not a masterfully delivered joke by one of my favourite comedians or the bantering between husband and wife. This was &lt;em&gt;just a talk&lt;/em&gt;, not written to entertain in a crude way, delivered supposedly to inspire and educate a group of creative professionals. This was different, was it not? Or was it different because it was &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; in the audience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never been one to be easily offended and it is a weakness of mine that I feel I must mention this in order to legitimize my response. It is with much restraint that I write this, as it is such a failure to me that I have to even address it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not identify myself as a female Designer or Entrepreneur. I go through great pains to remove gender from my life in any way possible because I believe that gender has no place in many conversations. Being a woman informs my life in the way that having black hair or ten fingers informs my life. My body is the cask in which I was put. Yet, here it was—a clear reminder that I was not like &lt;em&gt;them.&lt;/em&gt; Unfortunately, I am starting to realize that my approach is cowardly and at best, a naive way to look at the bubble in which I occupy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose I could never write well enough to articulate why what I saw made me uncomfortable. I can only say that describing the feeling as “discomfort” is insufficient. I felt awkward, confused, irritated and angry. I resisted taking off my rose-tinted glasses for so long because, after all, this is &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; industry. This is supposed to be where I feel the most comfortable. This is not only my job but my life’s work so far. At that point, it felt like an awfully unjustified vocation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I entertained the idea as I walked away from the conference that there was more than just the gender status quo playing out in front of me. That this problem is not merely a grouping of men who are socially-stunted in an industry that accepts and encourages their behaviour but also that this was willful ignorance in the face of talent. That our industry (but perhaps not just our own) fetishizes output so much that the thought of saying, “No” to what is clearly wrong is too absurd an idea to entertain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worry that speaking up causes side effects such as over-censorship or an over-reliance on “nanny culture.” I also worry that occasionally efforts to make things equal are overreaching and do so at the expense of the other group. What worries me most though, is that the ones who have the biggest potential to move the needle on this issue are the very ones who sat in the audience and laughed. What is left is a group of individuals who are expected to be politely angry lest they wish to be unfairly criticized or dismissed as prudes for saying, “No.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are musings without a purpose as I am sure there is not a simple solution to all of this. I do know, however, that this question has developed in my mind over the past couple of days about my place in all of this, “What is the cost of being politely angry?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;seperator small&quot; /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;This post was sparked by a talk I watched at Reasons to be Creative in Brighton. It is a good three-day conference/event held yearly targeted towards creative professionals. The last speaker of the conference spoke for just over an hour about his work and I wrote this roughly two weeks later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://helentran.com/2014/09/19/from-the-desk.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://helentran.com/2014/09/19/from-the-desk.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>JIBO and Our Relationships with Personal Electronics</title>
				<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;figure--large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;figure__img&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.twitrcovers.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Wall-E-l.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WALL-E&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;h6 figure__caption text-center&quot;&gt;WALL-E&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year marks the thirteenth year of my partnership with technology. I have dedicated my career and until recently, most of my free-time in technology-related pursuits. This year also happens to be the first year in which I have felt truly disconnected from the person that I had related to for the majority of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working and living with technology affords you lots of opportunities to live a great life. As I run into the bigger problems, however, I’m noticing that the solutions aren’t found in technology. The most soul-burning question I have at the top of my mind right now is, “What is all of this, really?” and that answer cannot be found in the face of an iPhone, humanistic robots or data-mining social media websites. What I’m looking for is found in other people, except that other people no longer appear to be as interested or involved in creating connections as they once were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Sherry Tuckle’s TED talk, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/sherry_turkle_alone_together&quot;&gt;Connected but alone?&lt;/a&gt;, she observes that the way we are looking at relationships is changing. People want to connect but only if the connection can be had at a distance, in amounts they can control. This need to control how we are perceived to others highlights an insecurity we have to not be faulty. In the digital age, you can be whoever you want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This purposeful distancing also makes us more prone to feeling alone. How we feel &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0069841&quot;&gt;when using Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, working in &lt;a href=&quot;http://devpressed.com/&quot;&gt;competitive online industries&lt;/a&gt; and when using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://psychcentral.com/news/2012/05/22/depression-linked-with-more-internet-use/38998.html&quot;&gt;internet in general&lt;/a&gt; is affecting our relationships and mental health. Is this the connected life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest social robot, JIBO, promises more than just individual companionship and basic administrative role-playing, it’s promises companionship to an entire family. In MIT Professor Cynthia Breazeal’s video pledge to crowd-fund JIBO, she rallies potential supporters,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…we need your help; to build JIBO; to bring it to the world and to grow the community. Let’s work together to make JIBO truly great. And together, we can humanize technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuckle’s talk is focused on about exactly this. We are seeking relationships with machines that are designed to be humanistic instead of looking to each other for these connections. These machines are programmed by someone to nod their heads or beep deeply in a effort to mimic human empathy. Do we want empathy or do we want mimicked empathy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;seperator small&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of the flurry of social apps we have created, we have become unable to sit by ourselves without filling the empty moments with other people’s lives. This addiction doesn’t come out of a desire to deepen connection and occasionally comes at the expense of the actual person in front of us. We have confused solitude with isolation and as a result, could potentially be leaving ourselves with only one: isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If we don’t teach our children to be alone,
they will only know how to be lonely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I don’t believe that exploring the idea of something like JIBO is not worthwhile, Breazeal paints a world in which technology is &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; than just a tool. Technology needn’t be that romanticized—it’s impacts are obvious and profound.Technology is a tool and I hope we always question the importance of the role it plays in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;
	&lt;hr class=&quot;seperator&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h5 class=&quot;resources__title&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
	&lt;ul class=&quot;resources__list&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/sherry_turkle_alone_together&quot;&gt;Connected, but alone?&lt;/a&gt; - Sherry Turkle studies how our devices and online personas are redefining human connection and communication&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.ca/Alone-Together-Expect-Technology-Other/dp/0465031463&quot;&gt;Alone Together: Why We Expect More from Technology and Less from Each Other&lt;/a&gt; - Her Book&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://helentran.com/2014/07/16/JIBO.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://helentran.com/2014/07/16/JIBO.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>This is Water</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;David Foster Wallace’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8CrOL-ydFMI&quot;&gt;commencement speech&lt;/a&gt; for Kenyon graduates in 2005 opens with a parable,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Two young fish are swimming along and they happen to meet an older fish swimming the other way, who nods at them and says, “Morning boys. How’s the water?” The two young fish swim on for a bit. Eventually one of them looks over at the other and goes, “What the hell is water?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David explains that many people will tell the graduates that the importance of education is to learn how to think. He says it’s much deeper than that–it’s about learning how to exercise control over how and what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I work in the tech industry, I get the privilege to work with some very smart people day in and day out. This has however come with an immense self-inflicted pressure to measure myself against the achievements of others. This also tends to lead to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;impostor syndrome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, something many people in the industry have identified with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ambition, when paired with my impatience, is crippling. Progress becomes invisible because I’m not looking for progress. When I’m comparing myself to others, worshipping their intellect, &lt;em&gt;I will never have enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David speech was a reminder that these people whom I consider to be more achieved are not relative to my own successes and failures. It is easy to think of the world &lt;em&gt;in relation to me&lt;/em&gt;–it isn’t easy to control my thoughts and push for a more productive outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has taken me years to understand what DFW talks about in his commencement speech. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is about the real value of a real education, which has almost nothing to do with knowledge, and everything to do with simple awareness; awareness of what is so real and essential, so hidden in plain sight all around us, all the time, that we have to keep reminding ourselves over and over:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“This is water.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“This is water.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;
	&lt;hr class=&quot;seperator&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h5 class=&quot;resources__title&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
	&lt;ul class=&quot;resources__list&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8CrOL-ydFMI&quot;&gt;This is water&lt;/a&gt; - David Foster Wallace&#39;s commencement speech&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://helentran.com/2014/06/25/this-is-water.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://helentran.com/2014/06/25/this-is-water.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Future of UI and the Dream of the &#39;90s</title>
				<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;figure--large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;figure__img&quot; src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/fit/t/1200/504/1*pgZ7j1E5fXoARz8zP18NDw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Minority Report (2002)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;h6 figure__caption text-center&quot;&gt;Minority Report (2002)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I once had an account where I was the only Designer on the team and the only female involved in building the product. The client was obsessed with integrating ‘social.’ Despite my &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/design-ux/be40f5485275&quot;&gt;general dislike&lt;/a&gt; of arbitrary social functions, they were adamant that it had to happen so I moved ahead with creating a heart icon to represent a ‘Like’ function. It was a small piece of a much larger UI redesign so I assumed it would be glossed over and I could focus on fighting the bigger battles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tested various animations for the action and a few hours later, the heart icon was axed by a developer. When further questioned, I found out that someone on the team decided it was too &lt;em&gt;feminine&lt;/em&gt; (i.e. too tied to our emotions) and that a man wouldn’t want to click on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure--large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;figure__img&quot; src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/800/1*rSzGnunTvBxVIwPbFJT27g.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The Matrix (1999)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;h6 figure__caption text-center&quot;&gt;The Matrix (1999)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My previous colleague’s refusal to add an emotionally-associated action to the app is a symptom of a pervasive obsession in the tech industry. The visual trend in interface design occasionally mimics interfaces out of past science fiction T.V. shows and movies. This is somewhat fair; the Designers who’ve spent their childhoods absorbing this media are now adults designing interfaces. We have been bombarded with imagery all the way back from the 70’s (albeit less frequent then) and this trend still persists today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure--aside&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;figure__img&quot; src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/720/1*dA1I96DLks2-dgNSLQ1Hpg.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Minority Report (2002)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;h6 figure__caption text-center&quot;&gt;Minority Report (2002)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This visual concept was seemingly fully formed towards the end of the 90s. Design aesthetics became systems of mathematically arranged lines, geometric shapes, numbers and cold colour palettes. All interfaces were stripped of humanistic elements aside from the occasional AI human face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this dream from the 90’s, we hoped for a world where every computer knows us personally. We would wake up to them, have them around us all day, and they would be the last thing we interact with before we go to sleep. They would predict our needs and wants and all interfaces would feel as natural as having a conversation with a friend. Technology would become our primary means (or only means) of communication and we would form relationships with these objects that take care of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In other words, we’re expected to translate our emotions through emotionless interfaces.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;seperator small&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All humans are capable of emotional depth. While emotions are influenced by culture, emotions themselves are universal. We use things because they are functional but we become attracted and attached to them because of how they make us feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-pursuit-of-delight-is-in-the-details&quot;&gt;The pursuit of delight is in the details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume for a bit that the product you are working on is purposeful and functional: it serves a need and the user can achieve what they need to do simply and quickly. This is only the first step. Now begins the pursuit of delight and this is what distinguishes &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; design from &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Frank Chimero’s, “The Shape of Design” he writes (emphasis mine),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The warmth and exuberance of communication and the accommodation to the audience necessitated by delightful design also makes it easier for the audience to spot the presence of the designer in the work. &lt;strong&gt;The work becomes more humanized in its tone and effect, so it becomes easy to see that there are people behind it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although technology has come a long way, it has not replaced face-to-face communication—we still need assurance that there is someone on the other side. While many users may not notice one or two details in a UI, they can feel the accumulation of those efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what tools do we have at our disposal? Designers can look beyond basic aesthetics to embed personality. Let’s take a look at sound, animation, and copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sound&quot;&gt;Sound&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound affects us &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/julian_treasure_the_4_ways_sound_affects_us.html&quot;&gt;physiologically, psychologically, cognitively, and behaviourally.&lt;/a&gt; While we are still discovering ways sound can be applied to application interfaces, there is an industry we can look to that has mastered the use of sound to provoke emotion—the gaming industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure--large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;figure__img&quot; src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1778/1*_4noQMUuNoTZYCCInkDWDQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Journey, developed by Thatgamecompany&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;h6 figure__caption text-center&quot;&gt;Journey, developed by Thatgamecompany&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journey is an indie video game showcasing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bkL94nKSd2M&quot;&gt;masterful use of sound&lt;/a&gt;. Austin Wintory, the game’s composer, based all the pieces on one theme that represented the player’s journey. The music dynamically responds to the user’s actions giving them immediate and personable feedback. The game designers’ efforts were rewarded with critical acclaim with many players describing it as “moving” or “religious.” Patrick Shaw, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wired_%28magazine%29&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt; said the game made him feel a “wide range of emotions… wonder, fear, even sadness.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While application interfaces probably don’t need to make use of immersive soundtracks, the addition of sound effects can add to a user’s experience (provided they have the option to opt-out.) Apps like &lt;a href=&quot;http://realmacsoftware.com/clear&quot;&gt;Clear&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.duolingo.com/&quot;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt; added cheery and triumphant sound effects to their completion actions. These sounds are a recognition of the user’s success and reinforces the visual mark of a, typically green, success state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure--large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;figure__img&quot; src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1400/1*QJsHjUtibE2ubJpCwaYZ0w.png&quot; alt=&quot;Clear (left) and Duolingo (right)&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;h6 figure__caption text-center&quot;&gt;Clear (left) and Duolingo (right)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation&quot;&gt;Animation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In UI design, we are afforded the luxury of using animation as a way to differentiate our products and interfaces from static billboards. When animation in a UI mimics movement we see in the natural world, we feel comfortable with it. Because we create emotional bonds to our physical environments, when we see this replicated it becomes personable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure--large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;figure__img&quot; src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1280/1*LSB1tM_f56e_nbwBrV9TnA.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Relating inanimate objects with human traits build emotional bonds that can last for days, months or even years&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;h6 figure__caption text-center&quot;&gt;Relating inanimate objects with human traits build emotional bonds that can last for days, months or even years&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pixar is one of the most successful animation studios of all time. They are at the forefront of their industry; masters at blending animation with human emotions. At Disney’s D23 Event in 2011, the Pixar Team panel was asked, “Is there one element in every Pixar film that makes a Pixar film a “special” film or “different” from any other film?” John Lasseter replied,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s the feeling you also got from the old Walt Disney films, like the feeling you got when Dumbo visits his mother who’s locked up, or when Bambi’s mother is killed, or the emotions we feel when Pinocchio is at Pleasure Island. It’s these deep emotions you don’t feel anymore in modern Hollywood films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pixar’s key to success is their understanding of the value of emotion and what drives someone to attach to their characters and stories—personal bonds and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;seperator small&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can we learn from the masters of animation and how can we apply that to our work in UI? Replicating what we see in everyday life reminds us of our personal experiences. In Disney animators Ollie Johnston and Frank Thomas’ book, &lt;em&gt;The Illusion of Life: Disney Animation&lt;/em&gt;, they outline 12 basic principles to creating more realistic animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not the key point of an interface, we can apply these animation principles on a micro-level. Excellent examples of delightful animation can be seen in &lt;a href=&quot;http://tapbots.com/software/tweetbot/&quot;&gt;Tweetbot&lt;/a&gt;, Apple Maps and &lt;a href=&quot;https://vine.co/&quot;&gt;Vine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item lap--one-third desk--one-third&quot;&gt;
		&lt;figure&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/800/1*Au4rpERhkCF2T9eVSG6wug.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Tweetbot&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;figcaption class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Tweetbot’s modal dismissal mimics the movement of a falling board.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
		&lt;/figure&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item lap--one-third desk--one-third&quot;&gt;
		&lt;figure&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/800/1*rOepebPEB-M5lSccThN6yg.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Apple Maps&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;figcaption class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Apple Maps’ pin drop feels like it would if you placed the pin there yourself. Falling slowly at first and then quickly pinning into place.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
		&lt;/figure&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item lap--one-third desk--one-third&quot;&gt;
		&lt;figure&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/800/1*W4-XfSE7WSk0nm9aNfkhpg.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Vine&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;figcaption class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;While simple, the animation in Vine feels more like a drawer opening than just a menu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
		&lt;/figure&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;copy&quot;&gt;Copy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While seemingly a very obvious way to communicate—copy and how we deal with inputs is often overlooked. In our rush to replace popular actions with iconography, designers often forget that sometimes copy can be just as powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can make use of copy to speak to users conversationally, eliminate the chore of form input or provide discoverable and fun easter eggs. All three ways give the illusion of a person behind the product or device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com&quot;&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt; encourages users not to shy away from development. Instead of leaving us with just their motto and brief description, they start a conversation with their potential students asking them simple questions to teach them how to use their interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1400/1*TPp-du6mxP9rf0S46zKJgA.png&quot; alt=&quot;Codecademy&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;h6 figure__caption text-center&quot;&gt;Codecademy’s conversational approach to education is approachable and unintimidating&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure--aside&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;figure__img&quot; src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/612/1*RMW9gz5b31Exn7jd7UtvRA.png&quot; alt=&quot;Fantastical&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;h6 figure__caption text-center&quot;&gt;Fantastical’s smart user input&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flexibits.com/fantastical-iphone&quot;&gt;Fantastical&lt;/a&gt; eliminates the tedious task of inputting meta data associated with your events by providing a smart input that automatically translates your conversational sentences into an event. Keeping organized is no longer a chore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;a href=&quot;http://realmacsoftware.com/clear&quot;&gt;Clear&lt;/a&gt;, which relies on a series of gestures for interaction, doesn’t require any additional copy to function well and provide value. However, the team has given us discoverable quotes only seen when you have a cleared list. This is not only fun but it serves as an reminder of why we’re using Clear. It celebrates our wins with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1141/1*EeEFoHgmGrKi_7wYMoj63g.png&quot; alt=&quot;Clear&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption class=&quot;h6 figure__caption text-center&quot;&gt;Clear’s discoverable copy inspires and serves as a small reward for a hard day’s work&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;seperator small&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the tech world, where solid competition pops up on a daily basis—convincing a user that they &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to use your product is key. By using sound, animation and copy Designers can endue delight into our interfaces providing users with opportunities to build attachments to our products. While Designers can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scifiinterfaces.com/&quot;&gt;learn a lot&lt;/a&gt; from our science-fiction dreams, we need to understand how to embed personality and emotional cues into our work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future of interface design isn’t a dream from the 90s. The future of interface design is about emotional awareness connecting us with products the way we connect with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;
	&lt;hr class=&quot;seperator&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/verneho&quot;&gt;Verne Ho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/evandinsmore&quot;&gt;Evan Dinsmore&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/travishines&quot;&gt;Travis Hines&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/woodifred&quot;&gt;James Wood&lt;/a&gt; for their feedback on this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;
	&lt;hr class=&quot;seperator&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h5 class=&quot;resources__title&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h5&gt;
	&lt;ul class=&quot;resources__list&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-ILLUSION-OF-LIFE-ANIMATION/dp/0786860707&quot;&gt;The Illusion of Life: Disney Animation&lt;/a&gt; - Thomas and Johnston, two of Disney&#39;s original animators write a book about the studio&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/julian_treasure_the_4_ways_sound_affects_us&quot;&gt;The 4 ways sound affects us&lt;/a&gt; - Playing sound effects both pleasant and awful, Julian Treasure shows how sound affects us&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amplifon.co.uk/emotions-of-sound.html&quot;&gt;Emotions of Sound&lt;/a&gt; - How do you feel when you hear these sounds?&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stoweboyd.com/post/33227418776/a-heart-is-different-from-a-star&quot;&gt;A Heart is Different from a Star&lt;/a&gt; - Airbnb talks about how hearts affect UI&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://useyourinterface.com/&quot;&gt;User Interface Library&lt;/a&gt; - Animation pattern library&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;99% Invisible-95- Future Screens are Mostly Blue&lt;/a&gt; - Lessons to learn from sci-fi&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://helentran.com/2014/01/18/the-future-of-ui.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://helentran.com/2014/01/18/the-future-of-ui.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
